<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Jake Gutierrez</title><link>https://jakegut.com/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Jake Gutierrez</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 12:09:01 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jakegut.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Gatsby to Hugo</title><link>https://jakegut.com/posts/gatsby-to-hugo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 12:09:01 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://jakegut.com/posts/gatsby-to-hugo/</guid><description>Recently, I wanted to update my website for the sake of having something new and different. When I opened up my the repository for my older website, I was taken back by the sheer complexity that Gatsby requires. I thought that updating my website would prove to be a headache. Gatsby uses GraphQL to get custom data from the file system, in my case a bunch of Markdown files. Having to rewrite or copy-paste GraphQL queries seemed kind of daunting to me since I&amp;rsquo;m unfamiliar with GraphQL, as well as making sure that all of my needed files where found by Gatsby.</description></item><item><title>RStudio Tutorial: Stacked and Side-by-Side Bar Graphs</title><link>https://jakegut.com/posts/rstudio-tutorial-stacked-and-side-by-side-bar-graphs/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 21:36:10 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://jakegut.com/posts/rstudio-tutorial-stacked-and-side-by-side-bar-graphs/</guid><description>This tutorial will go over how to create stacked and side-by-side bar charts in RStudio with ggplot.
To get started, make sure you have ggplot installed using
install.packages(&amp;#34;tidyverse&amp;#34;) tidyverse contains multiple different packages including ggplot.
Next, we&amp;rsquo;ll import the data set and include tidverse like so:
library(&amp;#34;tidyverse&amp;#34;) # The path of the file will depend on your machine, make sure it&amp;#39;s changed # accordingly movies = read.csv(&amp;#34;D:/Intro to Stats/Movies_06-15txt.csv&amp;#34;) And make a basic bar graph:</description></item><item><title>RStudio Tutorial: Histograms and Boxplots</title><link>https://jakegut.com/posts/rstudio-tutorial-histograms-and-boxplots/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 11:14:31 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://jakegut.com/posts/rstudio-tutorial-histograms-and-boxplots/</guid><description>This tutorial will go over how to use histograms and boxplots in RStudio. This tutorial assumes you know the basics of R and RStudio. Please follow this series on YouTube to grasp the basics of R and RStudio.
First off, make sure you have tidyverse and cowplot installed using:
install.packages(&amp;#34;tidyverse&amp;#34;) # And install.pacakges(&amp;#34;cowplot&amp;#34;) tidyverse includes the ggplot2 package which we will use the ggplot function from the package. cowplot allows us to add multiple plots into one image.</description></item></channel></rss>